hitslink.com 2013-12-16

# Privacy Statement | Net Applications

We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices.

**

## Your Information is Private

**  
Subscribers are requested to enter limited personal information during signups. Under no circumstance will we sell, transfer or disseminate this personal information gathered by our products to any other entity. 

Our statistics product collects information about visitors to the subscriber's website. This information will also not be sold, transfered or disseminated to any other entity. We may display aggregated data to show industry trends (such as browser share). However, this data shall be the average of many thousands of sites and will in no way linked to individual subscribers. 

**

## Your Information is Secure

**  
We employ the use of the following measures to ensure your data is secure: 

  * All accounts require an account id and password to view data.
  * Secure logins are supported (through SSL 128-bit encryption) for users concerned about their account id and/or password being viewed in transmission.
  * All data centers use firewalls and other extensive security measures to prevent unauthorized access to our internal networks.
  * The physical preservation of the data is ensured by the use of RAID-enabled servers, surge protectors, battery power backups, and daily data backups.  All servers are housed in climate-controlled data centers.

**

## Safe Harbor

**  
For Our European Union Clients/Customers: Net Applications has joined the U.S. Department of Commerce() 's Safe Harbor Program, and we adhere to the principles and guidelines set forth within Safe Harbor. 

If you believe that Net Applications is not in compliance with Safe Harbor, contact our company by mail, e-mail or telephone:

Net Applications  
65 Enterprise  
Aliso Viejo, CA 92656

866-784-5180

For more information about Safe Harbor, visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/sh_overview.html>

**

## Anonymous Information

**  
You can visit Net Applications' websites without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. To improve the effectiveness of our website, Net Applications measures and analyzes anonymous and aggregated statistical data from our website visitors in an effort to continuously improve our website performance and the quality of our service to you. 

The information we gather may include, but is not limited to, the following: the country of origin of the visitor, the visitor's navigation path within our websites, and the when the visitor is visiting our website. Net Applications reserves the right to publish anonymous, aggregate summary information regarding our website visitors. Please note that we neither collect nor store personal information from our website visitors. 

**

## Cookie Usage

**  
The use of cookies is limited to storing a small amount of non-identifiable information on a visitor's computer.  For visitors to our sites, the data is used only to maintain information about the user's session. 

For visitors to sites that have installed our statistics package, cookies are used to enhance the ability of our product to display usage patterns.  This information does not in any way reveal any personal data about visitors.  Visitors to a subscriber's site will receive a cookie that stores only a generic id, the prior page, time since last visit, and number of the visit. 

**

## Access to Personal Account Data

**  
Every subscriber is requested to enter limited personal information that is stored in our databases.  This information may include credit card information for pay subscribers.  At any time, subscribers may modify this information upon logging into the product using an account id and password.  Credit card information is only requested on secure pages (using SSL 128-bit encryption).  Credit card information is never re-displayed once entered. 

**

## Opt-In E-Mail Lists

**  
Every new subscriber has the option of not receiving site news and special promotional offers by either unchecking the opt-in check-box on the main signup form, or opting out of future mailings by clicking on the 'Opt-Out' link on any e-mail correspondance sent.  Once an user opts-out no further e-mails will be sent except for traffic alerts the user sets up and important administrative notices. 

**

## Children's Guidelines

**  
This web site meets the guidelines of TRUSTe's Children's program, which means that it does: 

  1. NOT collect online contact information without prior parental consent or parental notification, which will include an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity.  Without prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to the(child) 's request and will not be used for other purposes without prior parental(consent)
  2. NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information without prior parental consent
  3. NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information with out prior parental consent
  4. NOT give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent
  5. NOT entice by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity, to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity

**

## Contacting the Web Site

**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can(contact) 

**

## E-Privacy Directive by the European Union

** As many of you are aware the EU has begun to enforce their e-Privacy Directive, also known as the "Cookie Law." Its purpose is to help users gain a better understanding into how websites use cookies to track their behavior. You can find out more about it at the ICO.In order to make sure our partners and clients are aware of the new directive and are compliant with it, we’ve updated our Privacy Policy to answer a few FAQs on the topic.It is important to note that we at Net Applications are not attorneys. Please do not construe this information to be legal advice. This is our best assessment of the directive based on the information we have.

## When did the directive go into effect?

May 26, 2012.

 **

## Why did the EU feel there was a need for a directive? Are cookies scary?

** No, cookies are not scary. However, many people are unaware of what information they are sharing on the internet, and this appears to be what the EU is trying to address. We at Net Applications want to help educate people about how websites use cookies.

 **

## What is a directive – how does it compare to a law?

** Directives are passed by the EU, and are binding to the EU member states. However, they do not apply to EU citizens unless the directive is passed into law by the EU member states.

 **

## Does it apply to my website if I’m not in the EU?

** It is unclear if or how the EU will be able to enforce the directive against any website owner not residing in the EU.

 **

## What is a cookie?

** A small text file that contains a unique ID tag, placed on the user’s computer by a website.

 **

## What's a cookie's purpose?

** The main purpose of cookies is to identify users and possibly prepare customized web pages for them. They help you stay logged in to sites where you want this. They also can keep your shopping cart information while shopping online. Cookies do not contain viruses. They do not scan your computer for personal information.

 **

## Can I control my computer’s behavior with regards to cookies?

** Yes. At any time you can clear your cookies. You can also choose to opt out of some or all cookies via your browser settings.

 **

## Does it affect Me?

** It affects almost everyone who owns or visits any website. Almost all websites use cookies, and cookies are involved in all types of web activity including speeding up login pages and using Analytics programs to understand where visitors to your website have come from. The vast majority of cookies are beneficial to users, and are often used to help provide a more personalized experience for online users. Cookies are used by all sites across the web including Google, Facebook, YouTube and more to enhance the online experience. So, as a Net Applications Partner or Client, you need to be aware of the cookies that are on your own site and how those cookies affect your users.

 **

## How can I be sure I'm compliant, and what does "informed consent" mean?

** The UK's Information Commissioner’s Office has provided guidance, clarifying the directive to allow websites to rely on "informed consent" to comply with it. This means that you should take steps to let your visitors know what types of cookies you use on your site. If visitors are aware of the cookies, and still continue to visit your website, then you have achieved "informed consent" and are in compliance with the directive according to the ICO.

 **

## What are the cookies used by Net Applications and how are they used?

** Net Applications uses first-party cookies to count and analyze the traffic for our client websites. We do not access, store, or even know any personally identifiable information about the visitors to ours or our client websites. These are the cookies we use:  
\- Name: VSID, Domain: loc1.hitsprocessor.com  
\- Name: VSID, Domain: counter.hitslink.com
